Mitchell Stephens Papers
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
Mitchell Stephens Papers
1936 - 2022
Mitchell Stephens
npkmc-234-061
6.25 Linear Feet 15 Boxes 269 Folders
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
Published in 2017, The Voice of America: Lowell Thomas and the Invention of 20th Century Journalism by Mitchell Stephens is the first completed biography ever written on Lowell Thomas, an innovative journalist of the 20th century. The Mitchell Stephens Papers Collection includes research materials and drafts for the biography.
Acquisitions Information
Collection was donated to Marist College Archives and Special Collections by Mitchell Stephens on December 1, 2022.
Accruals Information
No accruals are expected.
Restrictions to Access
There are no restrictions on this collection.
Physical Access Restriction
Collection contains digital materials on a USB external hard drive which must be accessed with a computer.
Historical Note
Mitchell Stephens was born on August 16, 1949 in New York City. Stephens is a NYU Professor of Journalism and Mass Communication and author of numerous articles and 8 books including The New York Times "Notable Book of the Year,” A History of News. Before working on The Voice of America, Mitchell Stephens was interviewed by director Richard Moulton on a documentary he was doing on Lowell Thomas. Mitchell Stephens would work with Moulton again on the documentary Voice of America: Lowell Thomas and the Rise of Broadcast News (2019) in which Anne T. Donaghy, the granddaughter of Lowell Thomas, was an executive producer. While conducting projects with Richard Moulton, Mitchell Stephens began researching and writing The Voice of America. Stephens began researching and drafting the Lowell Thomas biography in 2014. While researching for the Lowell Thomas biography, Mitchell Stephens traveled to Ohio, Colorado, Yukon, Alaska and many of the same places Lowell Thomas visited and reported. Although Stephens did not read the manuscript drafts, he would consult the outline of the unfinished Lowell Thomas biography by Fred Crawford as the basis for his own book. Stephens would also consult many original materials including journals, travelogues, correspondences, photographs, and footage within the Lowell Thomas Collection at the Archives and Special Collections at Marist College.
Arrangement of the Collection
These records are organized into 6 series: 1) Manuscript Drafts, 2) Research Materials, 2.1) Chapter 1. A Portrait of the Journalist as a Young Cowboy, 2.2) Chapter 2. Two Scoops in Chicago, 2.3) Chapter 3. See America First, 2.4) Chapter 4. Too Good to Be True 2.5) Chapter 5. Something More Colossal Than Anything of its Kind Ever Tried, 2.6) Chapter 6. A Blue-Eyed, Beardless Man in Arab Robes, 2.7) Chapter 7. Come with Me to the Land of History, Mystery and Romance, 2.8) Chapter 8. How Dull It Is to Pause 2.9) Chapter 9. Having the Ear of America, 2.10) Chapter 10. The Voice of God, 2.11) Chapter 11. Catching Up with the War, 2.12) Chapter 12. The Very Roof of the World, 2.13) Chapter 13. An Entirely New Form of Entertainment, 2.15) Chapter 14. To Strive, To Seek, To Find and Not to Yield, 2.15) Additional Materials, 3) Correspondence, 4) Maps, 5) Photographs, 6) Digital Materials, 6.1) Manuscripts and Research Materials, 6.2) Lowell Thomas Photographs from Richard Moulton.
Collection Overview
This collection consists of materials created or saved by Mitchell Stephens, including his manuscript drafts and notes for The Voice of America: Lowell Thomas and the Invention of 20th Century Journalism, as well as articles on journalism and communication. Much of the collection consists of copies from the Lowell Thomas Collection at Marist College that have been annotated by Stephens. The collection also includes correspondence between Stephens and Richard Moulton and Anne T. Donaghy.
Deatiled Description of the Collection
- 1. Manuscript Drafts, 2014-2016; 1.; About 1.67 linear feet Boxes: 1 - 4 Folders: 78
  Series contains chapter drafts, notes, and corrections of the The Voice of America: Lowell Thomas and the Invention of the 20th- Century Journalism.
  Each chapter draft has been placed in its own folder and organized by the order of chapters as it appears in the book then chronologically by date. Discarded chapters or those with different titles are placed at the end. The folder titles correspond with the headers of each document which have the chapter number and title. Sometimes the chapter numbers change between drafts. The series also contains fact checks and corrections of chapters. The three notebooks are titled by the style and brand of the book as they were not given a title by Mitchell Stephens.
  - Prologue, October 30, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Prologue, October 30, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Prologue and 1. A Portrait of the Journalist, October 30, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Prologue, March 22, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Prologue and 1. A Portrait of the Journalist, March, 25, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Prologue, March 31, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 2. Two Scoops in Chicago, July 27, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 2. Two Scoops in Chicago, March 28, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 3. "See America First", July 27, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 3. "See America First", July 27, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 3. "See America First", July 27, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 3. "See America First", March 28, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 4. Too Good to Be True, August 14, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 4. Too Good to Be True, August 14, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 4. Too Good to Be True, August 14, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 4. Too Good to Be True, August 14, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 4. Too Good to Be True, August 14, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 4. Too Good to Be True, August 14, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 4. Too Good to Be True, August 14, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 4. Too Good to Be True, August 14, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 4. Too Good to Be True, August 14, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 4. Too Good to Be True, August 14, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 4. Too Good to Be True, August 14, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 4. Too Good to Be True, March 28, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 4. Too Good to Be True, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 5. Something More Colossal Than Anything of Its Kind Ever Tried, March 03, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 5. Something More Colossal Than Anything of Its Kind Ever Tried, March 29, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 5. Something More Colossal Than Anything of Its Kind Ever Tried, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 6. A Blue-Eyed, Beardless Man in Arab Robes, October 11, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 5. A Blue-Eyed, Beardless Man in Arab Robes, October 11, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 5. A Blue-Eyed, Beardless Man in Arab Robes, October 11, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 5. A Blue-Eyed, Beardless Man in Arab Robes, October 11, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 6. Come with Me to the Land of History, Mystery and Romance, January 17, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 6. Come with Me to the Land of History, Mystery and Romance, January 17, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 6. Come with Me to the Land of History, Mystery and Romance, January 17, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 6. Come with Me to the Land of History, Mystery and Romance, January 17, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 7. Come with Me to the Land of History, Mystery and Romance, March 29, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - 8. How Dull It Is to Pause, April 11, 2016 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - 9. Having the Ear of America, October 09, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 9. Having the Ear of America, December 21, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 9. Having the Ear of America, May 23, 2016 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 9. The Voice of God, August 14, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 9. The Voice of God, August 21, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 9. The Voice of God, August 21, 2015 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 10. The Voice of God, September 04, 2015 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 10. The Voice of God, October 09, 2015 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 10. The Voice of God, December 21, 2015 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 10. The Voice of God, April 04, 2015 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 11. Catching Up with the War, November 10, 2015 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 11. Catching Up with the War, November 19, 2015 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 11. Catching Up with the War, January 13, 2016 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 11. Catching Up with the War, April 26, 2016 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - 12. The Very Roof of the World, January 07, 2016 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - 12. The Very Roof of the World, January 13, 2016 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - 12. The Very Roof of the World, January 29, 2016 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - 14. To Strive, To Seek, To Find, and Not to Yield, April 25, 2016 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - 14. To Strive, To Seek, To Find, and Not to Yield, May 18, 2016 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 8. Rainbows Flying in Aeroplanes, August 03, 2015 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - 8. Rainbows Flying in Aeroplanes, October 09, 2016 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - 8. Rainbows Flying in Aeroplanes, December 21, 2016 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - 8. Land, Sea and Air, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - 8. Land, Sea and Air, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - 8. Land, Sea and Air, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - 13. High Adventure, February 26, 2016 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Lowell of America - first half, April 02, 2015 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Lowell of America Draft: First Half, April 05, 2015 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - The Voice of America Style Sheet, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Index, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Page 11 CK (Chapter 1 Check), July 11, 2016 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Page 160 CK (Chapter 8 Check), undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Page 205 CK (Chapter 13 Check), undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Page 265 CK (Chapter 13 Check), June 2016 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Page 302 CK (Chapter 14 Check), July 2016 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Melvis Acosta (Corrections), undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - College Ruled Compposition Notebook, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Staples Notebook, 2014 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Meade Notebook, 2015 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- 2. Research Materials, 1936-2016; 2.; About 3.75 linear feet Boxes: 9 Folders: 179
  This series consists of 15 subseries pertaining to materials used for research on Lowell Thomas. The first 14 subseries coincide with the 14 chapters of the Lowell Thomas biography, The Voice of America: Lowell Thomas and the Invention of 20th Century Journalism. The last subseries consists of new research materials. Many of the materials are copies of Lowell Thomas’ journals, letters, travelogues, and articles.
  The subseries are arranged by chapter titles in the order they appear in The Voice of America: Lowell Thomas and the Invention of 20th Century Journalism and the folders are arranged alphabetically. Original folder titles were kept. Items should be kept in orginal order as some pages are double sided with Stephen’s original work being front facing.
  - Subseries 2.1: Chapter 1. A Portrait of the Journalist as a Young Cowboy, 2014 - 2015; 2.1; Boxes: .5 Folders: 13
    Subseries includes research materials on Lowell Thomas’ early life including information on his family and where he grew up in Victor, Colorado such as copies of: Dr. Harry G. Thomas, “Cripple Creek at the Turn of the Century,” a chapter of an unfinished memoir by Lowell Thomas’ father and a transcript of a 1951 interview between Dr. Harry Thomas and Dick Roelofs; and 1997 Victor Elks Lodge #367 100th Anniversary book. Subseries includes History of Colorado, The Victor Record 1910-1911 on microfilm.
    Alphabetical
    - Dr. Harry Thomas, 2015 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Dr. Harry Thomas, 2015 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Dr. Harry Thomas, 2015 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Dr. Harry Thomas, 2015 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Dr. Harry Thomas, 2015 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Dr. Harry Thomas, 2015 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Victor, 2014 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Victor, 2014 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Victor, 2014 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Victor, 2014 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Victor, 2014 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Victor, 2014 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Victor (The Victor Record Microfilm), undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 2.2: Chapter 2. Two Scoops in Chicago, 2014; 2.2; Boxes: .5 Folders: 10
    Series contains research on Chicago in 1915 including copies of letters between Lowell Thomas and his parents between 1915 – 1916; and copies of Lowell Thomas’ journal from 1915.
    - Chicago, 2014 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Chicago, 2014 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Chicago, 2014 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Chicago, 2014 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Chicago, 2014 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Chicago, 2014 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Journal from 1915, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Journal from 1915, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Parents, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Parents, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 2.3: Chapter 3. See America First, 2014; 2.3; Boxes: 1 Folders: 21
    Series contains annotated copies of Lowell Thomas’ correspondence with his wife Frances Thomas and copies of Thomas’ journal during his early trips to Alaska. Also contains articles Stephens used as background information on Alaska.
    - Alaska, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Alaska, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Alaska, undated. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Alaska - Dans, 2014 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Alaska - Dans, 2014 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Fran, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Fran, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Fran, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Fran, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Letters to Fran - Alaska II - Princeton, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Letters to Fran - Alaska II - Princeton, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Letters to Fran - Alaska II - Princeton, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Letters to Fran - Alaska II - Princeton, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Letters to Fran - Alaska II - Princeton, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - More Fran Letters, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - More Fran Letters, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - More Fran Letters, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - More Fran Letters, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - New Chicago Journal, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - New Chicago Journal, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Untitled (Klondike Gold Rush), 2014 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 2.4: Chapter 4. Too Good to Be True, undated; 2.4; Boxes: .5 Folders: 11
    Series contains Includes annotated copies of Lowell Thomas’ journal and travelogue from 1916 to the beginning of World War I.
    - Princeton, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Princeton, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Princeton, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Princeton, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Travelogue, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Travelogue, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Travelogue, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Travelogue, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Travelogue, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Travelogue, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Travelogue, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 2.5: Chapter 5. Something More Colossal Than Anything of its Kind Ever Tried (WWI), undated; 2.5; Boxes: .5 Folders: 7
    Series contains annotated copies of Lowell Thomas’ travelogue and journal before World War I and copies of articles on WWI and Harry Chase.
    - Europe (Before), undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Europe (Before), undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Europe (Before), undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Europe (Before), undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Harry Chase, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - WWI Getting Ready, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - WWI Getting Ready, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Subseries 2.6: Chapter 6. A Blue-Eyed, Beardless Man in Arab Robes (Middle East and WWI), 2014; 2.6; Boxes: 1 Folders: 17
    Series contains copies of Lowell Thomas’ field journals of Arabia and the Middle East. Many of the research materials in this subseries are related to series 2.7: Chapter 7. Come with Me to the Land of History, Mystery and Romance.
    - Arabia, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Arabia, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Egypt and Palestine, 2014 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Egypt and Palestine, 2014 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Egypt and Palestine, 2014 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Egypt and Palestine, 2014 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Egypt and Palestine, 2014 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Egypt and Palestine, 2014 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Egypt and Palestine, 2014 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Europe After, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Germany, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Germany, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Germany, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Germany, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Germany, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - LT and Dr. John Mack, undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - The Shooting, undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Subseries 2.7: Chapter 7. Come with Me to the Land of History, Mystery and Romance, 2014-2015; 2.7; Boxes: .75 Folders: 15
    Series contains materials on Lowell Thomas and T.E. Lawrence in the 1920s including copies of “With Allenby in Palestine.” There are also copies and criticisms of “The Show” and of Lawrence in Arabia.
    - The Show, 2015 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - The Show, 2015 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - The Show, 2015 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - The Show, 2015 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - The Show, 2015 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - The Show, 2015 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - The Show, 2015 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - The Show, 2015 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - The Show, 2015 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Untitiled (With Allenby in Palestine), 2014 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Untitiled (With Allenby in Palestine), 2014 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Untitiled (With Allenby in Palestine), 2014 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Untitiled (With Allenby in Palestine), 2014 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Untitiled (With Allenby in Palestine), 2014 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Untitiled (With Allenby in Palestine), 2014 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 2.8: Chapter 8. How Dull It Is to Pause, undated; 2.8; Boxes: .25 Folders: 3
    Series contains information regarding the Fred Crawford papers at Marist College includes a copy of Crawfords list of Books by Lowell Thomas. Also included is a copy of Good Evening Everybody by Lowell Thomas.
    - Misc. LT, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Misc. LT, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Misc. LT, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Chapter 9. Having the Ear of America, 2015 - 2016; 2.9; Boxes: .75 Folders: 12
    Series contains copies of articles on the history of early radio in the 1920s and 1930s, as well as annotated copies of Lowell Thomas’ scripts of radio shows.
    - Radio, 2015 - 2016 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Radio, 2015 - 2016 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Radio, 2015 - 2016 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Radio, 2015 - 2016 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Radio, 2015 - 2016 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Radio, 2015 - 2016 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Scripts Early, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Scripts Early, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Scripts Early, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Scripts Early, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Scripts Early, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Scripts Early, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 2.10: Chapter 10. The Voice of God, 2015; 2.10; Boxes: .25 Folders: 4
    Series contains copies of newspaper articles on clubs Lowell Thomas was involved in during the 1930s and 40s. Also includes copies of articles on T.E. Lawrence’s death and broadcast in 1935. There are also copies of essays and articles on television and shows in the 1940s.
    - Clubs 1940s, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Lawrence Death Broadcast, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Newsreel Fox, 2015 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - TV 1940s, 2015 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 2.11: Chapter 11. Catching Up with the War (WWII), 1936 - 2015; 2.11; Boxes: 1 Folders:15
    Series contains a 1936 Sunoco Oil Election Year Facts edited by Lowell Thomas, copies of essays on the Holocaust along with copies of Lowell Thomas’ journals and reports on World War II.
    - Holocaust, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Jimmy Doolittle, undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Quaker Hill 1940s, 2015 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Radio 1940s, 2015 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Sun Oil - Dew, 1936 - 2015 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Sun Oil - Dew, 1936 - 2015 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - WW II Journals, undated (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - WW II Journals, undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - WW II Journals, undated (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - WW II Journals, undated (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - WW II Journals, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - WW II Journals, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - WW II Journals, undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - WW II Journals, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - WW II Journals, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 2.12: Chapter 12. The Very Roof of the World, 2015; 2.12; Boxes: .2 Folders: 3
    Series contains copies of articles and essays about the Dalai Lama of Tibet and the war against communism during the 1940s and 1950s which Lowell Thomas reported on.
    - Tibet, 2015 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Tibet, 2015 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Tibet, 2015 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 2.13: Chapter 13. An Entirely New Form of Entertainment, 2015 - 2016; 2.13; Boxes: .75 Folders: 12
    Series contains research on Cinerama and television, including Lowell Thomas’ High Adventure during the McCarthy era in the 1950s.
    Alphabetical/Chronological
    - Cinerama, 2016 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Cinerama, 2016 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Cinerama, 2016 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Cinerama, 2016 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - High Adventure, 2015 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - High Adventure, 2015 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - High Adventure, 2015 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - High Adventure, 2015 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - McCarthy, 2016 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - McCarthy, 2016 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - McCarthy, 2016 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - 1950s, 2015 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Subseries 2.14: Chapter 14. To Strive, To Seek, To Find, and Not to Yield, 2015 - 2016; 2.14; Boxes: 1 Folders: 22
    Series contains annotated copies of journal articles, newspaper articles, and obituaries regarding the last three decades of Lowell Thomas’ life from 1960s to 1981 and his legacy afterward. There is also a National Geographic reprint from July 1964 by Mrs. Lowell Thomas, JR. Also includes articles about the film, Lawrence of Arabia.
    - Antartica, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Capital Cities, 2016 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Capital Cities, 2016 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Capital Cities, 2016 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Capital Cities, 2016 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Christl, 2016 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Denver University, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Dewey Death, 2016 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Eichman, undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Late Fran, undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Lawrence Film, 2016 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Lawrence Film, 2016 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Lindbergh, undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Lowell's Death, 2016 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - LT Jr., undated (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - LT Jr., undated (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Marianna, 2016 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - News Obituaries and Interviews, 2015 - 2016 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - News Obituaries and Interviews, 2015 - 2016 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Other Shows - LT, 2016 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Skiing, undated (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - This Is Your Life, 2016 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Subseries 2.15: Additional Materials, 2015-2016; 2.15; Boxes: 1 Folders: 14
    Series contains copies of Fred Crawford’s letters and outline of unfinished Lowell Thomas biography. Also included are copies of Lowell Thomas’ indentures and an untitled transcript.
    - Crawford Letters, undated (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Crawford Outline, undated (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Indenture Copies, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Indenture Copies, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Indenture Copies, undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Indenture Copies, undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - New Materials, 2015 - 2016 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - New Materials, 2015 - 2016 (Box 14, Folder 6)